

Wojciech Gołuchowski Java Backend Developer

My professional experience and interests are focused around backend technologies incl. Java, databases and distributed systems. In order to get the most out of my work I strive to understand the business domain and requirements that are the drivers for the software being created. I'm always open for new challenges like working with new languages, technologies, tools and methodologies, as well as sharing knowledge.

Personal information

Date of birth 1990-10-30

Address ul. Ogrodowa 17/100 61-821 Poznań

E-mail wojciech.goluchowski@gmail.com

Skype w.goluchowski

Phone number +48 730468240

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/wojciechgoluchowski/

Key skills & technologies

Java, Spring Framework, Spring Boot JPA, Hibernate, REST-API, JMS, Kafka, Microservice architecture, SQL – Microsoft SQL Server, PostgreSQL, SAP HANA, NoSQL – Cassandra, Neo4j Maven, Gradle, Git, Jira, Scrum, Linux, Docker, Web Security

Languages

English – advanced German – basic Polish – native

Professional experience

2016-11 - 2021-06

Palturai Sp. z o. o., Java Developer | Backend

Worked in a Scrum team of 6 along with Germany-based product owners. Designed, implemented and optimized microservice-based platform for processing and analyzing data of companies, institutions and people related to them.

Stack: Java, Scala, Spring, Kafka, Hibernate, PostgreSQL, Neo4j, Cassandra, Spark, Solr, REST-API.

2015-10 - 2016-10

GFT Poland Sp. z o. o., Java Developer

Worked in international team (3 different time-zone locations) on a high performance billing software for investment banking. Stack: Java, Spring, JMS, Oracle Coherence

2013-11 - 2015-07

BeOne Sp. z o. o., Java Developer | Business Analyst

Developed DMS software for companies and public institutions based on Alfresco platform. Analyzed business requirements, implemented, deployed and gave training to the users.

Stack: Java, Spring, Alfresco, BMPN, PostgreSQL, JasperReports

2012-07 - 2013-10

Integra Software Sp. z o. o., C++ & SQL Developer

Developed ERP software and reporting tools for automotive industry. Stack: Microsoft Visual C++, C#, SQL Server, Fast Reports

Education and training

2021 - 2022

edu.devstyle.pl, Droga Nowoczesnego Architekta Training: Domain-driven design, general architectural topics

2013 - 2015

Poznań University of Technology, Faculty of Computing Second cycle studies of Computer Science, Specialty: Data Processing

2009 - 2013

Koszalin University of Technology, Faculty of Electronics and Computer Science

First cycle studies (Bachelor of Science) of Computer Science, Specialty: Computer Programming and Networks